PROFESSOR: So now let's answer
it for depth-first search.
Well, what does depth-first search do?
Well, remember we saw it kind of stripes
from left to right, so it
expands everything on the left.
And if it doesn't find a goal, it kind
of keeps trucking rightward until it
hits a goal.
Which goal does it hit?
It hits kind of the leftmost goal, if
you consider left to be whatever order
the successors get prioritized
by the implementation.
OK, so it expands some left
prefix of the tree.
It means we could do the whole tree,
like what's our worst depth-first
search nightmare?
Where is the goal?
It's like, over here.
And we process the whole tree, right?
Remember, processing the
whole tree is bad news.
Processing half of the tree is half bad
news, which means it's bad news
because everything's exponential here.
And so if m is finite, this thing's
going to take time, b to the m to find
the solution in general.
Or you might luck out, it might be on
the left, but in general, you should
expect to process a chunk of the tree.
And the tree is extremely big.
All right, how much space does my fringe
take up while I do this order b
to the m work?
Well, what's on my fringe?
It's all these other things at the
top level that we didn't do yet.
And then below that, it's all the things
we didn't do at that level, and
all the things we didn't do.
So it's basically along this path
to wherever I am right now.
It's all of the other successors
on the path to the root.
Well, there's b successors
at every level.
I can be at most m deep.
And so since we only have siblings on
the path to the root, it's b times m.
The fringe is small.
OK, that's something in depth-first
search's favor.
OK, is this algorithm complete?
Now we can finally answer
the question.
We've got our tree.
We can answer the question.
If there is a solution, am
I guaranteed to find
it with this algorithm?
The rub is how big can m get?
Think back to the other quiz
with the four state graph.
M could be, say, infinite.
OK, b to the m is bad enough
when m is finite, right?
So b to the m can be very big.
If m is infinite, then this is
in fact will not be complete.
We could spin our wheels just going
downward to the left, kind of, and
never stop.
So what could we do?
We could prevent cycles somehow.
There are various ways of doing these.
We'll find out one way next class, which
will have to do with removing
redundant work in general.
So if m is finite, either because you've
eliminated cycles in some way,
or because the graph is finite to begin
with, then this may be complete.
But only in cases where
you won't get cycles.
Is it optimal?
That is, if there are multiple
solutions, am I guaranteed to find the
cheapest one?
I haven't really even told you what
costs are, but imagine everything has
cost one for the moment.
Am I guaranteed to find the
shallowest solution?
Here's the shallowest solution.
We're sad because we don't find it.
OK, so it doesn't.
It finds the leftmost solution.
In general, people could
not care less about the
leftmostness of the solution.
You want to find the cheapest one in
some way, and that's a disadvantage to
depth-first search.